FERNANDO GALVAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

San Antonio

PHONE

210-965-5343

EMAIL

n.brighter00@gmail.com

SKILLS

HTML5

Linux

Microsoft Office

CSS

HTML

jQuery

Node.js

React

C#

SQL

Git

Python

JavaScript

AWS

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

LANGUAGES

Spanish

• • • •

PROFILE

Driven and unrelenting professional looking to bring 10+ years of crucial experience in solution implementation, data analytics, and multi-department coordination into the software development world. Proven to meet deliverables by proactively learning, practicing and implementing new methodologies and technologies. Passionate about complementing a team to better reach our goals.

CERTIFICATION

General Assembly - Full-Stack Academy

San Antonio

Feb 2022 — Aug 2022

- · Built various applications using JavaScript and Python
- · Built servers using Express.js, Node.js
- · Created databases for servers using PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS
- Built front-end applications using libraries such as Bootstrap, MaterialUI, ReactJS, Django and Flask.

Developer Associate - Amazon Web Service

San Antonio

Oct 2022 — Dec 2022

· Currently pursuing certificate to better assist with back-end needs.

PROJECTS

E-Commerce Store

Technologies Used - ReactJS, Express.js, Node.js, MaterialUI, JavaScript, MongoDB, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Redux

- · Cart functionality with add/reduce & remove items.
- · Page responsiveness
- · Connected to API built in Node.js and host on Heroku

Crypto Currency App

Technologies Used - ReactJS, MaterialUI, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Antd, BootStrap

- · Rendering Cryptocurrency detail from RapidAPI
- · Responsiveness for mobile devices.

TV-Show Search

Technologies Used - Python, Django, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

- · Search functionality attached to TheMovieDataBase API service
- Mobile responsiveness

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jan 2022 — Present

- Reduced invoicing discrepancies by implementing weekly audits of field work reports.
- · Reduced payment delays by streamlining billing procedures.
- · Increased revenue by 20k by reducing fuel and labor inefficiencies.
- · Led acquisition of new contracts and new clients.

Operations Specalist, New Generation Excavation

San Antonio

Apr 2021 — Dec 2021

- · Implemented new work schedule reports and logs.
- Reduced communication inefficiencies between managers and clients by implementing single channel.
- Created workflow procedures that allowed all managers to audit work efficiently.

Operations Coordinator, Veryable

San Antonio

Oct 2018 — Mar 2021

- · Trained all market clients to proficiently use on-demand platform.
- · Increased app activity 50%> using different marketing campaigns.
- Curated detailed reports and analytics on how clients increased growth and production using platform.

Billing Coordinator, Envision Physician Services

San Antonio

Aug 2017 — Sep 2018

- Reduced billing turn-around times by 24 hours by building new processes and invoicing templates.
- Trained all staff on Microsoft Office suite products to reduce communication disparities.
- Implemented error tracking report to assist with new software implementation.

Claims Analyst, UnitedHealth Group

San Antonio

Oct 2015 — Jun 2017

- · Made Top-Performers list multiple months in a row.
- · Mentored new analyst on compliance expectations.
- · Led training efforts which reduced review time and increased approval rates.
- $\cdot\;$ Assisted team which focused on high-dollar claims.

EDUCATION

B.S. - Psychology, Univeristy of Texas at San Antonio

2008 - 2013

B.S. - Business Administration, Southern New Hampshire Univeristy

2015 - 2017